MCQ = [
    
     {"question":"Who developed Python Programming Language?",
       "options":["Wick van Rossum","Rasmus Lerdorf","Guido van Rossum","Niene Stom"],
       "answer":"Guido van Rossum"},

       {"question":"Which type of Programming does Python support?",
       "options":["object-oriented programming","structured programming","functional programming","all of the mentioned"],
       "answer":"all of the mentioned"},

       {"question":"Is Python case sensitive when dealing with identifiers?",
       "options":["no","yes","machine dependent","none of the mentioned"],
       "answer":"yes"},

       {"question":"Which of the following is the correct extension of the Python file?",
       "options":[".python",".pl",".py",".p"],
       "answer":".py"},

       {"question":"Is Python code compiled or interpreted?",
       "options":["Python code is both compiled and interpreted","Python code is neither compiled nor interpreted","Python code is only compiled","Python code is only interpreted"],
       "answer":"Python code is both compiled and interpreted"},

       {"question":"All keywords in Python are in _________", 
       "options":["Capitalized","lower case","UPPER CASE","None of the mentioned"],
       "answer":"None of the mentioned",},

       {"question":"What will be the value of the following Python expression?",
       "options":[7,2,4,1],
       "answer":7},

       {"question":"Which of the following is used to define a block of code in Python language?",
       "options":["Indentation","Key","Brackets","All of the mentioned"],
       "answer":"Indentation"},

       {"question":"Which keyword is used for function in Python language?",
        "options":["Function","def","Fun","Define"],
        "answer":"def"},

       {"question":"Which of the following character is used to give single-line comments in Python?",
        "options":["//","#","!","/*"],
        "answer":"#"}
    
    ]